# 黄金炒饭
Golden fired rice
# 每一粒米饭 都粘满了蛋黄
Every grain of rice is covered with egg yolks
# 所以它成为黄金炒饭
So we called it “Golden fried rice”
# 头天的剩米饭 一般炒饭都是剩米饭
We often used leftover rice
# 润润锅 家里边有不粘锅的
Add some oil to prevent sticking
# 咱就不用聊了 怎么都不粘
If you use non-stick fry pan, we don't need to do the rest steps. It is not sticky
# 怎么润呢 我的工作经验告诉我
From my work experiences
# 一定要把油加进去
Add some oil first
# 然后慢慢的让它加热
Then heat it up slowly
# 怎么也得到六成以上 关火多焖一会儿
heat it for at least 60 percent (180 C). Turn off the heat and leave it for a while
# 这样它的油会渗进去一些
In order to let oil seeps in
# 在热的时候表面它就不粘了
When the pan is hot, it will not stick
# 热的时候它是往上顶气
Steam will rise while the pan is hot
# 准备点什么料呢 我看准备了蛋黄了
What did you prepare for ingredients? I have prepared egg yolks.
# 炒米饭黄金色是由蛋黄来完成的
Fired rice’s golden comes from the egg yolks
# 那么米饭来讲
For rice
# 新米饭和隔夜饭
Freshly cooked rice or leftover rice
# 都没有什么太大的问题
Are both okay
# 那么主要是米饭焖完之后
After the rice is finished
# 表面它不能开花
Make sure it doesn’t break down
# 开花炒完之后 表面它就
If it’s broken
# 达不到那种光洁度了 就很散
It will not be as smooth as a whole grain of rice
# 再有一定要检查
Next, double check
# 米好坏的程度是哪里
The extend of the rice’s quality
# 蒸熟之后淀粉它会糊化
When steamed, there is starch gelatinization going on
# 糊化之后是晶莹剔透的
If the rice is crystal clear after gelatinization
# 这应该是新米
That should be fresh rice
# 如果蒸熟之后又散花 还不剔透
If it’s not, the rice is broken and not clear
# 那证明是陈米 炒饭就不好炒了
That should be old rice, it will be harder to make fried rice
# 所以一炒它就会碎掉
Old rice tends to break down when you fry it
# 它难以呈现是粒粒分明
So it’s hard to be separated from each other
# 锅润的差不多了
The pan is moist enough to prevent sticking
# 先别着急 关小火 等着它没关系
Don’t worry, turn to low heat and wait
# 时间越长 它润的越透彻
Pan will be moister as time goes on
# 它就更不容易粘锅
It will more likely to prevent stick-pan
# 咱们这些米饭需要放三个蛋黄
We need three egg yolks for these amount of rice
# 你看到没有
You see
# 今天隋师傅先把鸡蛋拌到米饭里边
Mr. Sui mix the yolks with the rice first
# 金黄金黄的
Golden
# 米饭如果在冰箱里拿出来比较凉
If the rice is still cool after taking out from the fridge
# 凉了之后下锅
Fry it when it’s cool
# 需要很长时间才会热
Will take a long time to heat up
# 我们就不如放在微波炉里边
we can put it in the microwave
# （提前）给它简单加热一下
Heat it up beforehand
# 加热到二十来度三十来度不冰手
Around 20 to 20 degrees Celsius
# 而且它容易散
Cool rice tends to break down
# 为什么隔夜饭有的时候好炒
Why we prefer to use leftover rice
# 它其实就是不容易粘锅 它容易散开
because it will not stick to the pan
# 再有 特别凉的米饭放到锅里边
Moreover, extremely cold rice
# 它特别容易扒锅
Are likely to stick to the pan
# 温度的反差 温度反差太大了
Due to the extreme difference in temperature
# 拌匀了就行了
Mix it thoroughly
# 咱们这个锅润透了
The pan is moist enough
# 开火 炒米饭的锅一定要干净
Turn on fire and make sure the pan is clean
# 看它有没有黑渣子 很干净
Look, it’s not black, means it’s clean
# 这就证明炒饭没问题
So it’s good for frying
# 它不会影响咱们出菜的整体的颜色
Since it will not contaminate the rice
# 放点葱油 增加炒饭的香气
Add some green onion oil to add some aroma
# 葱 要想让它炸出香味
Green onion, if you want the aroma to release
# 就得变成金黄色
It should turn gold
# 金黄色容易出黑渣
But it will be blackish when it’s gold
# 所以咱们就食其味不见其物
So we just eat it instead of seeing it
# 温油 三成热
Heat the oil around 30 percent (90 C)
# 下锅之后 不着急扒拉它
Don’t fry it immediately
# 慢慢的 下面凝固了 再扒拉一下
Fry it when it’s solidified underneath
# 完了再凝固上面的
Then fry it to make the rice above to solidified
# 您快速炒 有可能这个蛋就脱掉了
It you fry it too quickly, the egg will separate from the rice
# 就小火不着急 慢慢让它成熟着
So just take your time and stay in low heat
# 米饭粒越整越晶莹剔透
The longer it takes the clearer the rice
# 这黄颜色越好看
And the goldish the color
# 然后旁边锅热了 咱们炒蛋白
Another pan has heated up, let’s fry the egg whites
# 一是不浪费 二是增加一个颜色
Because we don’t want to waste and it will add some color to the fry rice
# 不着急 凝固就行
Don’t worry, wait until it’s one piece
# 然后加点盐调味
And season it with salt
# 鸡蛋当中含有谷氨酸钠
Eggs contain sodium glutamate
# 所以就不用再加味精了
So there’s no need to add MSG
# 然后把配料加进去
Then add other ingredients
# 蛋白差不多了
Egg whites are almost done
# 你看这颜色 中火
Look at that color, medium heat
# 黄白分明 加上胡萝卜青豆 颜色美观
Golden and white, along with the carrots and peas
# 黄金炒饭 出锅啦
Finished! Golden fried rice
# 好香 真香 太香了
Aromatic
# 你看着啊 每粒米饭
Look, every piece of ice
# 咱把蛋白往边上扒拉扒拉
Put the egg whites on top
# 都粘满了蛋黄
Are stick with egg yolks
# 所以它成为一个黄金炒饭
So it is called “Golden fried rice”
# 颗粒饱满 比原来米饭粒显着大了吧
Every grain of rice is big and full
# 而且松软 弹香 特别润
And its fluffy, aromatic and bouncy
# 所以米饭作为一个厨师的基本功来讲
As a fundamental  skill for chef,
# 它是挺考验人的
Rice I changeling
# 看似一盘炒饭
Fried rice seems to be easy
# 但是它体现出一个厨师的烹饪技巧
But it represents a chef’s cooking skills
# 和他的基本功的呈现
And it’s fundamental works
# 看起来简单
Seems easy
# 实际上炒饭 作为一个厨师
Actually fried rice,
# 在行业当中这块
in the industry
# 是一个最难的一件事
Is the hardest thing to cook
# 你看在香港搞大赛
You see, the cooking competition in Hong Kong
# 人家也不炒什么烧海参弄鲍鱼
They don’t test on how to cook sea cumbers and abalone
# 炒饭 炒牛河
They compete in fried rice and beef chow fun
# 大爷这个饭我最有记忆
Da Ye,I have some deep memory about this fried rice
# 您最有发言权 我还真有发言权
I am qualified to talk here
# 我看到这个饭 就想起一件事来
Seeing this rice, I recall one event
# 原来我记得在天伦王朝炒这饭的时候
When I am in Tian Lun Wang Chao, I was going to fry rice
# 香港人把那火弄好了 把饭搁这
Hong Kong chef set the fire and put the rice here
# 然后直接到我这炒
When it’s my turn to cook
# 炒出就有啰嗦
The rice doesn’t seem to be clear
# 然后我记得香港大厨 我是副的
I am the sous chef, then I remembered the executive chef in Hong Kong
# 他把那饭给我拽回来了
Take away my fired rice
# 带点啰嗦 这不行 给我拽回来了
Says it’s not clear enough
# 从那之后我长记性了
After that, I learnt the lesson
# 记着一辈子这事儿
Remember this for my whole life
# 香港人他不告诉你 特别难炒
Hong Kong chef didn’t tell me my mistake, and it’s hard to figure out
# 但是我们今天诠释的都非常清楚
But today we introduce all the steps very clearly
# 你照这方法一掌握就会了
You can get it easily when you cook along